Guide to the Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society collection FA1424
Rockefeller Archive Center
Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society collection
1985-2016
Rockefeller Archive Center
Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society
Ford Foundation
FA1424
.76 Cubic Feet 2 document containers
Scope and Contents
The Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society collection contains clippings, LAFF directories, correspondence from LAFF members (relating to dues, former Ford contacts, and life updates), correspondence between LAFF leadership, LAFF Society newsletters from 1991-2016, and correspondence regarding LAFF newsletter editorial choices.
Biographical / Historical
The Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society is an independent, volunteer-led association of men and women who have spent some phase of their careers working for the Ford Foundation. The Society was formed in 1991 by former staff members, led by Edward Meade, Jr. and Richard Magat, who wanted to stay in touch with their colleagues as they went on to other assignments or retired. LAFF was the first alumni group for former employees of a philanthropic foundation. From its inception, the expenses of the LAFF Society have been covered by annual dues and voluntary contributions from members.
The membership of LAFF includes those who served with the Foundation either in New York or overseas. In addition, local chapters have been formed in cities where members are geographically concentrated — Boston, New York and Washington in the United States, and overseas in Bangkok, Beijing, Cairo, Jakarta, Manila and New Delhi.
Arrangement
The Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society collection is arranged into two series:
1. Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society Membership Correspondence
2. Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society Newsletters
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2016 and 2017 by the Life After Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2016:058 and 2017:011.
Ford Foundation
- Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society Membership Correspondence, 1985-2003; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  - The LAFF Society Directories and Event Guest Lists, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    The LAFF Society Directories - 1996, 1998, 1999; LAFF Dinner Guest List October 21, 1993; LAFF Conversation Attendance List September 22, 1998 at the Sage Foundation
  - A, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Verne S. Atwater, James W. Armsey, Alma Armstrong, Jerome W. Anderson, Walter E. Ashley, Brent Ashabranner
  - B, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    May Bently, Carl, Tom Bayard, Peter D. Bell, Ralph G. Bohrson, Gordon Berlin, Anthony Bottrall, Bohrson, Samuel Bunker, Mary-Hart Bartley, Alison Bernstein, Lillian Brown, John Bresnan, Judy Barsalou, Piero Bronzi, Dyke Brown, Lillian Berg
  - C, 1991-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Robert Curvin, Mary Camper-Titsingh, John Cole Cool, John R. Coleman, Crossland, Matthew Cullen, Fred E. Crossland, Marie Castagnetta, Bob Castagnetta, Philip H. Coombs, William D. Carmichael, Richard M. Catalano, Sol H. Chafkin, J. Roger Carter, Steve Cox, Elsie I. Capozzi, Patricia Carlson, Lincoln Chen, Mariam Chamberlain, Robert W. Chandler, Jay Carol, Marion Coolen, Ralph Cummings
  - D, 1988-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Howard Dressner, Peter E. de Janosi, Nancy Dennis, David B. Dreiman, Mary (Kinney) Dwyer, John Doran, Robert H. Edwards, David M. Davis, Pat (Goebel) D'Alton, Richard W. Dye, Anita Meyer Dye, Robert S. Drysdale, Matthew Dagg, Charles Di Stefano
  - E, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    John W. English, Junie Eddy, John Ehle, Howard Elliott, Charles Di Stefano, John Krauss
  - F, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Mrs. John H. Funare, Frances D. Ferguson, Suzanne Foldes, Jonathan Friedman, David Freeman, Paul H. Feinberg, Linda Pappas Funsch, J. W. "Wayne" Fredericks, W. H. Ferry, William P. Fuller, Melvin J. Fox
  - G, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Lloyd M. Garrison, Edie and Bob Greene, John Gerhart, Susan Goodwillie, William P. Gormbley, Jr., Bernice R. Gordon for S. T. Gordon, Felice Gaer, Adrianne Grunberg, G. H. (Bill) Griffiths, Evelyn Garcia, William K. Gamble, Leslie Gottlieb, William J. Grinker, Davidson R. Gwatkin, Dennis Gallagher, Robert B. (Bob) Goldman
  - H, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Lowell S. Hardin, Goran Hyden, Harold Howe II, Iris Harris, Lillith M. Haynes, Mary Hannon-Haley, Helen Horn, Gordon Harrison, Ralph W. Harbison, Fred Harvey Harrington, David R. Hunter, Disbrow Hadley, Bud Harkavy, Joan Hall, Stanley Heginbotham, Peter Gubser, Reed Hertford, William J. Hertz, Donald S. Harris, David Heaps, Ulric "Rick" Haynes, Jr.
  - I, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    James Taylor Ivy, Warren Frederick Ilchman, Caroline Iltis, Barbara Lethem Ibrahim
  - J, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    A. A. Johnson, William T. Irelan, Arlene Feder Juter, Michael S. Teitelbaum, Sanford M. Jaffe, Warren F. Ilchman and Alice Stone Ilchman
  - K, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Moselle Kimbler, Florence Knippchild, Louise W. Keady, John E. Kerrigan, Mary Ann Korzan, James A. Kelly, W. Kiene, Harold A. Klein, Joan Krauss, Doris Kenry, Marian S. Krauskopf, Ursula L. Kreutzer, Eamon M. Kelly, Starry Krueger, Gladys Krasner (?), Roger G. Kennedy, Richard Kapp, Terrance Keenan
  - L, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Roberto L. Lenton, Charlotte Larrabee, Ivo John Lederer, Linda Knoepfle, W. McNeil Lowry, Terry Lisniewski, Jeri Laba, Gilbert Levine, Richard Longhurst, Roberto Lenton, Richard T. Mahoney, Laura Lake, Oleg Lobanov, Ann M. Lesch, Felice Michaels Levin
  - M-Mc, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Mabel Muller, David T. McDonald, Janet McNeely, Sheila Avrin McLean, Porter McKeever, Nancy McCarthy, Jane McCarthy, David T. McDonald, Anthony R. Measham, Ghebre Selassie Mehreteab, Marjorie Martus, Kathryn H. Mitchell, Natalie Millner, Richard T. Mahoney, Diana Morris, Alice Maloney, Robert A. Mayer, Anita Miller, Marjorie Martus
  - N, 1985-2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Ruth Neumann, Susan T. Newman, John S. Nagel, Quigg Newton, Courtney Nelson, Barbara Scott Nelson, Brenda A. (Cox) Newman
  - O, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Alice O'Connor, Cecile Ousmane, Sally Oleon, Siobhan Oppenheimer-Nicolau
  - P, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Jane Plakias, Harrison Parker, Don K. Price, Jr., Edward Preston-Guess, William C. Pendleton, Jeffrey M. Puryear, Kristin Pauly, Michel Petit, Bill Pincus
  - R, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Marshall Robinson, Gustav Ranis, George Rosen, Kathleen A. Reynolds, William S. Reed, William J. Rust, Kay Ryan, Marshall Robinson, Peter Ruof, James Rose, Talton F. Ray, Delwin A. Roy
  - S, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Francis Sutton, Theodore M. Smith, John Sommer, Adolph Suehsdorf, Thomas V. Seessel, Robert Schmid, Ivy F. Steber, Richard S. Sharpe, Terry Tinson Saario, Robert C. Seaver, Sheldon J. Segal, Eugene S. Stedman, Theodore J. Shannon, Jeswald W. Salacuse, Henry Saltzman, Dolores Stanley, Jerrold Stivers, Adie Suehsdorf, David R. Smock, Robert Schmid, Nancy Sheldon, David Speckler, Christopher Welna and Betsy Station, Don Sandberg, Robert Schrank, Paul A. Strasburg, Joseph Elliott Slater, Mitchell Sviridoff, Tom Seessel, Stuart F. Sucherman, Terry Tinson Saario
  - T, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Robert Tolles, Franklin Thomas, Arthur D. Trottenberg, James Trowbridge, James Tierney, Shirley Teper, Pam Tice, Marian G. Weber, C. Gregory Tonning, Jane L. Barber Thery
  - W, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Thomas Wolf, Thomas H. Wright, Christopher Welna and Elizabeth Station, Basil Whiting, Robert Wickham, Marian G. Weber, F. Champion Ward, Evelyn C. Walsh, Libby Watterson, Abe Weisblat, Lou Winnick, Vivian Millicent Warfield
  - X, Y, Z, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Nancy Zimmerman, Paul Ylvisaker, George Zeidenstein
- Life After the Ford Foundation (LAFF) Society Newsletters, 1990-2016; 2
  Arranged chronologically
  - Press Materials and Assorted Documents, 1993-2009 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newsletter Editorial Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - LAFF Newsletters, No. 1-65 (missing no. 21), 1991-2011 (Box 2, Folder 26-28)
    Folder 26: No. 1-20 (1991-1999),
    Folder 27: 22-45 (1999-2006),
    Folder 28: 46-65 (2006-2011)
  - LAFF Newsletters, No. 83-84, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - LAFF Officer Notes and Correspondence, 1990-2009 (Box 2, Folder 30)